Guide to the Student Action With Farmworkers records, 1950-2020, bulk 1992-2016 RL.01128
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Printed Material, 1978-2016 and undated; 14 boxes
  - Non-SAF Publications, 1978-2016 and undated
    - Word Wide: Writers of the Americas / World Wide: Escritores de las Américas, program guide to public readings, workshops, cultural events, 2000 January-April; 2 copies (Box 94)
    - Youth Villages magazine, Spring, 2012 (Box 103)
  - Children's Books, 1993-2012
    Contains children's books, some bilingual, about migrant farmworkers and families.
    - Amelia's Road, Alman, Linda Jacobs and Enrique O. Sanchez, 1993 (Box 114)
    - Calling the Doves, Herrera, Juan Felipe, 1995 (Box 114)
    - Gathering the Sun, Ada, Alma Flor, 1997 (Box 114)
    - Piñata Books for Children, Spring 2011 and 2012 (Box 102)
    - Radio Man, Dorros, Arthur, 1993 (Box 114)
- Joan Preiss Papers, 1950-2005 and undated; 5 boxes
  Joan Papert Preiss was a frequent collaborator of SAF and a community and labor movement organizer in Durham, N.C. Among her roles were: chair of the Triangle Friends of the United Farm Workers; board member of the National Farm Worker Ministry; and member of the Farmworker Ministry Commission, N.C. Council of Churches.
  This series contains a variety of printed materials, primarily articles and newsletters, as well as correspondence, protest ephemera, promotional material for unions and activist organizations, meeting notes, etc. Undated materials are organized by subject. The series also contains student papers and photographs. The materials relate to migrants and farmworkers both in North Carolina and throughout the United States. Folders are organized chronologically.
  Along with the standard restrictions of this collection, Boxes 3 and 4 are RESTRICTED due to the inclusion of student papers. Please contact the Rubenstein Library for permission to use this box.
  - 1950-1984 (Box 80)
  - 1985-1999 (Box 81)
  - 2000-2007 (Box 82)
  - Student papers, 1979-2000 (Box 82)
  - Student papers, 1979-2000 (Box 83)
  - Articles and newsletters, undated (Box 83)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 83)
  - Ephemera and promotional material, undated (Box 83)
  - Notes, undated (Box 83)
  - Pamphlets and booklets, undated (Box 83)
  - Write-in forms, petitions, and donation forms, undated (Box 83)
  - Photographs, 1984-1999 and undated (Box 83)
  - Preiss, Joan Papert memorial service, 2012 (Box 98)
  - Oversized materials, 2004 and 2005, 2 items (Box 84)
- Ephemera and Artifacts, 1965-2013 and undated; 11 boxes 11 boxes; 3 oversize folders
  Contains materials, many of them oversize, related to Student Action with Farmworkers' organized protests and boycotts against entities such as Burger King, Subway, Gallo, and Mt. Olive Pickle Company, and products such as tomatoes and grapes. Some relate to the Chavez-led boycotts in the Southwest and agricultural worker protests in Florida.
  Items include posters, protest signs, banners, oversize puppets, wristbands, bumper stickers, T-shirts, buttons, and other items. Also contains artifacts from the Levante activist theater group, and other SAF ephemera.
  - Taco Bell (Oversize-box 85)
    Protest materials related to the tomato industry.
  - Burger King (Oversize-box 85)
  - Subway (Oversize-box 85)
  - AG Mart (Oversize-box 85)
  - Tomatoes, general (Oversize-box 85)
  - Protesting Folgers and promoting fair trade coffee at Duke (Oversize-box 86)
  - Mount Olive Pickle Company (Oversize-box 86)
  - Gallos (Oversize-box 86)
  - Outreach and meeting information (Oversize-box 87)
    Includes material featuring schedules, club members, activity reports, plays, etc.
  - General protest materials (Oversize-box 87)
    These materials do not identify a specific company or industry.
  - B&B Products and Sun Beauty Yams (Oversize-box 88)
  - Outreach and meeting information (Oversize-box 88)
  - Prime Mushrooms (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Campbell's (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Subway tomatoes (Oversize-folder 2)
  - General protest materials, outreach and meeting information (Oversize-folder 2)
  - Cloth banner for Triangle Friends of the United Farm Workers (Oversize-folder 3)
  - Public relations and outreach (Box 90)
    Newspaper articles, publications, etc.
  - AFL-CIO boycott ephemera (Box 90)
  - Taco Bell (Box 90)
  - Subway (Box 90)
  - Miscellaneous newspapers, 1965-1982 (Box 90)
    El Malcriado, La Cronica (photocopies), Ruby, Tobacco Road
  - National Farmworkers Awareness Week Posters, 2013 (Box 90)
  - Student drawings, undated (Box 90)
  - T-shirts (Box 91)
  - Write-in campaign postcards (Box 91)
  - Stickers (Box 91)
  - Mug (Box 91)
  - T-shirts (Box 92)
  - AFL-CIO flags/banners (Box 92)
  - "Uvas No" pins (Box 92)
  - "Fast for Life" medal (Box 92)
  - Ni de Aquí/Ni de Allá, Not from Here/Not from There (book) (Box 93)
  - "Recollections of Home" poster (Box 93)
  - Mask (Box 93)
  - Artwork (Box 93)
  - Plastic banner (Box 93)
  - Samantha - American Rights at Work award ceremony materials (Box 94)
    Photographs, certificate
  - Pesticide test kit from AFL-CIO (Box 94)
  - "Migrant farmworkers earn our support" bumper sticker, undated (Box 106)
  - Quinceañera celebration photograph, 2007 August 10 (Box 106)
  - "Immigrant rights are civil rights" sign, undated (Box 106)
  - Association of Migrant Students t-shirt, undated (Box 106)
  - Puppet, 2003-2004 (Box 107)
    Big Papa is a puppet that was used by SAF's theater group from 2003-2004 to represent the negative aspects of corporate agriculture. The puppet was created by NC sculpture artist Daniel L. Mathewson (1964-2011) for the play Gigantes en los Campos/Giants in the Fields written by NC writer Cara Page. The Big Papa character had few lines, but loomed ominously over scenes in the play as a method of intimidation and mockery of the farmworker characters. The play critiqued the H2A Guestworker Program which brings thousands of farmworkers to labor in the fields of North Carolina picking tobacco, cucumbers and other crops.
  - "Sí, se puede" rubber wristbands, undated, 4 items (Box 114)
  - "I support SAF in WNC! Got food? Thank a farmworker!" magnetized sign, undated (Box 114)
    "I Support SAF in WNC! Got Food? Thank a Farmworker!"
  - Grape and wine boycotts bumper stickers, 1990s? (Oversize-box 147)